Trevor Sammis

67 Richardson St. Apt 3R Brooklyn, NY 11211 (202) 557-0200 trevor.sammis@gmail.com

Overview

I have been leading professional development courses in web development and working as a contract web developer since 2007. I am experienced in HTML, CSS, Javascript, as well as jQuery and other Javascript frameworks. As a developer, I have worked with a diverse client base on a wide variety of projects. I have professional experience with Object Oriented Programming, JSON, and many third party Javascript libraries. As a teacher, I have taught intensive courses at The White House Communications Administration, M.I.T., Duke University, Blue Cross, Macy's, Tory Burch, The U.S. FDA, and The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, among many others. I am a CompTIA Certified Technical Trainer, an Adobe Certified Expert and Adobe Certified Instructor qualified to teach Dreamweaver, Captivate, Flash, and Actionscript 3.0. Additionally, I teach courses in Javascript, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3, Mobile & Responsive Web Design, PHP/MySQL, HTML email (email marketing). Over the past decade I have built a broad and adaptable web development skill set.

Recent Production Experience

Verizon FIOS / Accuweather

Remote

Built the Verizon FIOS Accuweather Channel widget (channel 119 in New York); consumed July 2015 JSON from Accuweather and built JS logic for Verizon FIOS front end

U.S. Defense Intelligence Agency

Remote

Built and consulted on interactive map/directions "wayfinding" application, using OOP July 2015 Actionscript and Adobe Flash.

Liberty Mutual Insurance

Philadelphia, PA

Built interactive SVG world map application with zoom-in functionality, using HTML5, December 2014 Javascript, jQuery, and third party libraries.

Scientific Games Middletown, PA

Rebuilt Scientific Games' Keno application used by several State Lottery systems, using Use July 2014 HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript.

Scientific Games Middletown, PA

Built and consulted on Scientific Games' Keno Flash application, used by several State
June 2012 Lottery systems, using Adobe Flash and OOP Actionscript.

Teaching Experience

General Assembly

New York, NY

Front-End Web Development Instructor

October 2015-present

- ! Taught longitudinal, ten week courses to classes of more than thirty adult learners
- ! Taught novice students HTML, CSS, Javascript, and jQuery
- ! Facilitated completion of individual mobile-ready websites, made by each student
- ! Managed two paid teaching assistants for each course

ThinkBig Columbia, MD

Instructor September 2012-present

! Taught classes including HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, ¡Query, PHP, and MySQL

- ! Consulted on curriculum development for new courses
- ! Taught a portion of classes remotely using Cisco WebEx

Future Media Concepts, Inc., *Adobe Authorized Training Center* Instructor

New York, NY March 2008-present

! Lead training sessions in twenty U.S. cities, and internationally in Dubai, U.A.E.

- ! Taught many Adobe courses including Dreamweaver, Captivate, Flash, and Actionscript
- ! Taught custom on-site classes, worked with ASL interpreters

Philadelphia, PA

Instructor

March 2011-2014

HTML5 Digital Classroom (Video Series)

Philadelphia, PA

Technical Reviewer

January 2012

Professional Certifications

All certifications are current.

W3Schools Certified HTML5	2014
W3Schools Certified Javascript Developer	2014
W3Schools Certified jQuery	2014
W3Schools Certified PHP / MySQL Developer	2014
Apple Certified Support Professional	2014
Recertification for Adobe Dreamweaver CS6	2013
Recertification for Adobe Flash CS6	2013
Adobe Certified Expert: Captivate CS5	2011
Adobe Certified Expert: Dreamweaver CS4	2010
CompTIA CTT+	2008
Adobe Certified Instructor in Flash CS3: Flash Video	2008
Adobe Certified Expert: Flash Professional 8	2007

Education

University of Richmond B.A., Biology, English

Richmond, Virginia

2003

References

Professional endorsements from clients and co-workers available upon request.